SOVAN PAUL

FRONT END DEVELOPER

CONTACT INFO

- +91 8777525898
- sovanpaul43@gmail.com sovanfronted01@gmail.com
- Barrackpore Kolkata West Bengal, India
- github.com/Sovanpaul

EDUCATIONS

BACHELORS OF COMPUTER APPLICATIONS

Adamas University | Kolkata 2016 – 2019 71%

HIGHER SECONDARY (SCIENCE)

Barrackpore A.B. Model High School | Kolkata 2014 – 2016 50%

MADHYAMIK

Barrackpore A.B. Model High School | Kolkata 2014 52%

ABOUT ME

My name is **Sovan Paul.** A Passionate Front End Developer with 2+ years of experience using, HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap, to build Static, Single Page and Responsive Websites. I am always looking forward to learn new things to improve my skill sets.

WORK EXPERIENCES

FRONT END DEVELOPER

INTERNSHIP - FULL TIME
SOURAV SIR'S CLASSES | KOLKATA | Nov 2019 - Oct 2021

- Here I was responsible for designing and developing the new web sites and maintaining those websites.
- SEO management.
- Handling Social Media Accounts.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

INTERNSHIP

ARANEUS TECHNOLOGY | KOLKATA | Jan 2019 - Jun 2019 Here I did designing and developing the Front ends of the web sites.

CAMPUS AMBASSADOR

INTERNSHIP

PAYTM | KOLKATA | Jul 2018 – Sep 2018 Organizing Digital Payment Awareness Camps to some Colleges.

SOVAN PAUL

FRONT END DEVELOPER

STRENGTHS

- Adaptability
- Creative
- Teamwork
- Good Listener
- Detail Oriented

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

- Asana
- MS word

LANGUAGES

- BENGALI Speaking / Written
- ENGLISH Speaking / Written
- HINDI Speaking

INTERESTS

Chess

Travelling

Currency collection

Spirituality

Stories

TECHNICAL SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT

- HTML
- CSS
- JAVA SCRIPT
- BOOTSTRAP
- ANGULAR.JS
- TAILWIND CSS
- PHP
- WIX
- SHOPIFY

DESIGNING

- PHOTOSHOP
- ADOBE XD
- FIGMA

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Responsive Web Design
- Understanding of SEO
- Converting PSD to HTML
- Automated Cross Browser Testing
- Knowledge on Single page websites
- Social Media handling

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

FIRST DEVISON IN 4TH YEAR FINE ARTS EXAM
SARAHBHARATIYA SANGEET AND SANSKRITI PARISHAD
2014 – 2015

1ST POSITION IN COLLEGE PHOTOGRAPHY COMPETITION

ADAMAS UNIVERSITY | 2017